<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>
			Security parameters
		</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<section name="1. SECURITY PARAMETERS">
			<OL type="I">
				<li>
					<a href="admin-user-security.html#a1._PARAMETRES_DE_SECUTITE_AVANCES">Security parameters</a>
				</li>
				<ol>
					<li>
						<a href="admin-user-security.html#a1.1_Introduction">Introduction</a>
					</li>
					<li>
						<a href="admin-user-security.html#a1.2_Paramètres_de_sécurité_avancés">Advanced security parameters</a>
					</li>
					<ol>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#parametres_de_securite_avances">Advanced security parameters</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a
								href="admin-user-security.html#activation_parametres_de_securite_avances">Use advanced security parameters</a>
						</li>
					</ol>
					<li>
						<a href="admin-user-security.html#a1.3_Gestion_des_mots_de_passe">Passwords management</a>
					</li>
					<ol>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#contraintes_mots_de_passe">Passwords format</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a
								href="admin-user-security.html#changements_mot_de_passe_obligatoire">Force a user to change his password</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#changements_mot_de_passe">Users password change</a>
						</li>
					</ol>
					<li>
						<a href="admin-user-security.html#a1.4_Gestion_des_comptes_utilisateur">Users account management</a>
					</li>
					<ol>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#tentatives_connection">Back office connections</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#duree_de_vie">Account life time</a>
						</li>
						<li>
							<a href="admin-user-security.html#anonymisation">Anonymization of an account</a>
						</li>
					</ol>
				</ol>
			</OL>
			<subsection name="1.1 Introduction">
				<p>
					From the Users management page, a technical admin user can define
					some security parameters.
				</p>
				<p>
					The security parameters management page can be accessed from the
					"Managers > Users management" menu, and by clicking on the
					"Advanced parameters" button on the upper right of the screen.
				</p>
				<p>
					Security parameters are located in the "Modification of security
					parameters values" panel.
				</p>
				<center>
					<img alt="Advanced parameters" src="images/param_secu.gif" />
				</center>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="1.2 Advanced security parameters">
				<a name="parametres_de_securite_avances" />
				<h4>1.2.1 Advanced security parameters</h4>
				<p>Security parameters can be decomposed in 2 groups :
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>basic security parameters</li>
					<li>advanced security parameters</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					Advanced security parameters can be activated or deactivated from
					the "Advanced Parameters" screen. They can only be modified when
					they are activated.
				</p>
				<p>
					Basic security parameters can be modified at any time.
				</p>

				<a name="activation_parametres_de_securite_avances" />
				<h4>1.2.2 Use advanced security parameters</h4>
				<p>
					On the "Advanced Parameters" screen, an admin user can turn on or
					off the advanced security parameters by clicking the upper left
					button.
				</p>
				<p>
					When advanced security parameters are turned on, password
					encryption is set on, and the encryption algorithm is set to
					"SHA-256". If the algorithm was not "SHA-256", then every user's
					password is reinitialized and sent by email.
				</p>
				<p>
					While advanced security parameters are on, the encryption
					algorithm can not be changed, nor the password encryption can be
					disabled. Although, it is possible to modify advanced security
					parameters in the "Modification of security parameters values"
					panel. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Security parameters can be deactivated by deleting their value,
					or by setting it to '0'.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="1.3 Passwords management">
				<a name="contraintes_mots_de_passe" />
				<h4>1.3.1 Passwords format</h4>
				<p>
					To prevent users from using low security level passwords, two
					constraints can be applied :
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>Password minimum length</li>
					<li>Usage of upper and lower case letters, of numbers and special
						characters</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					The minimum length of a password can be set with the parameter
					"Minimum length of a password". If the value is null or '0', then
					users can use passwords with any length. If it is greater than '0',
					users will have to choose passwords longer than the given number.
				</p>
				<p>
					If the check box "Passwords must contain upper and lower case
					letters, numbers and special characters" is checked, user's
					passwords will have to contain at least an upper and a lower case
					letter, a number and a special character. 
				</p>
				<p>
					<strong>Warning, the modification of this values will not force
						users to reinitialize their passwords.</strong>
				</p>
				<p></p>

				<a name="changements_mot_de_passe_obligatoire" />
				<h4>1.3.2 Force a user to change his password</h4>
				<p>A user can be forced to change his password
				</p>
				<p>
					For example, if the check box "Force user's password modification
					after a password reset" is checked, then users will have to change
					their password when they reset it.
				</p>
				<p>
					If advanced security parameters are activated, an admin user can
					also set a password life time. It will force users to frequently
					change their password. 
				</p>
				<p>
					Passwords life time, in days, can be set with the parameter "Days
					before a user must change his password".
				</p>

				<a name="changements_mot_de_passe" />
				<h4>1.3.2 Users password change</h4>
				<p>
					Users can be forced to use new passwords when they change it. The
					parameter "Number of old passwords remembered" contains the number
					of different passwords users have to use before they can choose a
					password twice.
				</p>
				<p></p>
				<p>
					To prevent users from changing their passwords many times to be
					allowed to use the first one again, their is a maximum number of
					password change in a given time. This can be set with two
					parameters : 
				</p>
				<ul>
					<li>"Maximum number of password change in a given time"</li>
					<li>"Number of days considered for password change"</li>
				</ul>
				<p>
					The first parameter is used to define the maximum number of
					password change in a given time. The second parameter is used to
					define the numbers of days users have to wait before they can
					change their passwords when they change it too many times.
				</p>
				<p>
					For example, if the parameter "Maximum number of password change
					in a given time" is set to '1', and the parameter "Number of days
					considered for password change" is set to '1', users will only be
					allowed to change their passwords once a day.
				</p>
			</subsection>
			<subsection name="1.4 Gestion des comptes utilisateur">
				<a name="tentatives_connection" />
				<h4>1.4.1 Back office connections</h4>
				<p>
					To protect passwords from being discovered by attempting a huge
					number of possibilities, a maximum number of login trial can be
					set. It will use two parameters.
				</p>
				<p>
					The first parameter is the "Maximum number of login attempt". It
					defines the maximum number of attempts someone can make before
					being blocked. The second parameter is the "Login attempt
					interval". It defines the duration, in minutes, a user is blocked
					when his login attempts failed too many times.
				</p>

				<a name="duree_de_vie" />
				<h4>1.4.2 Account life time</h4>
				<p>
					Each user account has a life time. If an account is not used
					during a given time, it expires. When an account expires, an email
					is send to the user so that he can update it. If he does not in the
					given time, then the account is definitively anonymized, and can
					not be used anymore.
				</p>
				<p>
					The life end date of an account is computed when the account is
					created, and is updated at each login of the user. Thus, only
					inactive accounts expires.
				</p>
				<p>
					Account life time, in months, can be set with the security
					parameter "Account life time".
				</p>
				<p></p>
				<p>
					Before an account expires, users are warned by an email
					containing a link to update it. It is possible to define the time
					between the expiration of an account and the first alert sent with
					the parameter "Time before first alert when an account expires".
				</p>
				<p>
					Other alerts are also sent to users by email. Parameters "Number
					of alerts" and "Time between alerts" define their frequency.
				</p>
				<p>
					To edit emails sent, choose in the drop down list of the
					"Notifications" panel the email to edit, and click the "Edit email"
					button.
				</p>
				<p>
					It is possible to define the title of emails, the sender and the
					body. In the body, some tags are replaced with values when the
					email is sent. Tags are like "
					<i>${tag_key}</i>
					". The list of available tags is on the left bottom of the page.
				</p>
				<a name="anonymisation" />
				<h4>1.4.3 Anonymization of an account</h4>
				<p>
					When an account expires, it is anonymized. Data of an anonymized
					account are encrypted, and it can not be used anymore. Attributes
					to anonymized can be chosen from the the anonymization management
					page, accessible from the user management page ("Managers > Users
					management").
				</p>
				<p>
					It is also possible to anonymize an account from the user management
					screen ("Managers > Users management") by clicking the "anonymize"
					button. 
				</p>
			</subsection>
		</section>
	</body>
</document>       
             
