<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>
            Lutece : Features
        </title>
    </properties>

    <body>
        <section name="Main caracteristics of Lutece">
            <subsection name="Organization of the portal">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            A site conceived by means of Lutece can be represented as
                            a tree structure of dynamic pages, whose root is the home
                            page.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The data presented in each page of the portal coexists inside 
                            blocks called portlets. These page headings are text zones
                            ,which can be inserted dynamically within a page by the webmaster
                            during conception or the update of the pages. Each page is 
                            associated to a model composed of rows and columns.
                            up of a model.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The technical data used to organise the site (i.e. pages, headings, content type, style sheets ..) are stored
                            in the database.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Navigation">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            The main pages of the site are grouped into a navigation 
                            bar which is always visible.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The direct access to the inner pages is done through the 
                            sliding menus associated to each main page of the site.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            An interactive navigation path is present on each visited
                            page. 
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The navigation through the tree structure within the site can
                            be accessed directly by placing links onto the page ( towards the
                            daughter pages ).
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The website plan, generated dynamically, allows direct 
                            access to pages of the site. 
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Services">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            The management of a set of services is maintained by XPages
                            which are always visible ( search engine, site plan,
                             chat, newletter, contacts, links towards other websites )
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Some open-source softwares have been added as services
                            ( full-text indexing, search engine ).
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>
                                <strong><u>Portlets and content type</u></strong>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The portlets, within which is placed web content, have 
                                a known type, depending on its content. The available
                                portlets are article list( news, agenda ,..), data sheets,
                                normal text or HTML, XML Document, person list, Downloadable 
                                files, internet links list, naviagation links list within 
                                the site, Web syndication( RSS format). 
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The insertion of the portlets into a page follows a composition model
                                , which organises itself into rows and columns ,can be fully parametrizable. 
                                The page-setting is also controlled by style sheets(CSS).
                              
                            </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>
                                <strong><u>Seperation between content and presentation</u></strong>
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The seperation of content and view is possible by opting
                                for XML as the exchange format. The XML files consist
                                of structured data, extracted from the database.
                       
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                The dynamic rendering  of page content is managed by the
                                transformation of XSLT content from XML data and style 
                                sheets associated to each portlet. 
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                Models for page-setting are predefined for each portlet
                                type and can be completed to satify possible future needs. 
                            </p>
                            <p>
                                A page is recalculated( integrated cache management ) 
                                only when its content has changed. 
                              
                            </p>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Tool to manage page-setting of the portlets">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            The administration tool is designed for webmasters of 
                            the portal and also publication assistants.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            This tool was conceived to simplify use and does not 
                            require particular skills.
                            
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            A set of graphical interfaces assists the webmaster 
                            during the creation of the pages, the choice of the
                            page headings, the entering and publication of content,
                            and also the choice of the presentation style
                            
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            A preview window allows the webmaster to see the page 
                            on which he is working and can thus interact 
                            directly on his content.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The construction of the pages of the portal and update
                            are done into a pre-production environment.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The additions or updates brought in pre-production
                            are committed after the validation of the webmaster.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The HTML content is editable through a WYSIWIG editor
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
          
           <subsection name="Tool to manage the services">
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        A list of persons to contact is exposed on the portal .This list is managed through the 
                        administration tool. 
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        It is also possible to manage a page of "Useful links", within which
                        the webmaster inserts the portlets of type useful links.
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Tool to create user accounts">
            <p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        The profile  ® administrator  ¯ gives right to create 
                        webmaster accounts and external contributor accounts.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        The profile ® webmestre¯ gives right to create all the 
                        user accounts needed to produce content or assist the 
                        publication process.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Each user account is binded to a content producer account,
                        to whom is associated a set of one or more information 
                        channels. The information channel defines a unique context to 
                        each producer( right to access information , type and origin 
                        of the information ).
    
                    </li>
                </ul>
            </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Tool to produce content">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            The tools for content are designed for 
                            webmasters and for different external contributors.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                        
                            The production of content consists of the typing of articles
                            or data sheets, with the help of an integrated text editor.
                            An image can be associated to each content produced.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The contents are produced without details on future 
                            page-setting( rule to seperate content and page-setting )
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Webmaster can upload Image libraries and downloadable files 
                            which he can insert in his portal. He can also simply insert
                            links in portlets ( through the "linkservices" ) which points towards
                            xpages, useful link lists, local actors.  
         
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
            
            <subsection name="Tool to publish content">
                <p>
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            The tool to publish web content into the site is designed
                            for the webmaster and for the publication assistant.
                            This tool gives access to all content added by contributors
                            and even gives a preview before effective publication.

                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The publication is the association of an article to different kinds of 
                            portlets, which have also different content type.
                            ( list of articles or datasheets ).
                        </li> 
                        <li>
                            An article can be published on different spots of the website
                            and is shaped in different ways. ( title only, title, image and summary, starting date and expiry date ).
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            The validity of the article is managed at the level of
                            its properties and determines its visual aspect.
                        
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            It is possible to bind an information channel to a
                            portlet, to automatize the publication of the produced
                            content on this specific channel.
                        </li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
