<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <document>
   <properties>
    <title>
      Lutece : Development Guide : Integrated Applications (XPageApplication)
    </title>
   </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Create the integrated application (XPageApplication)">
        <subsection name="The extended Lutece Pages(XPage)">
            <p>
               In Lutece, we can distinguish two types of page :
               
            </p>
            <p>
               <ul>
                  <li>the classic pages assembled by portlets. 
                      It concerns most pages on the website.
                  </li>
                  <li>Extended Pages which have a particular management scheme
                  which facilitates application realisation due to to its flexible
                  approach.
                  </li>
               </ul>
            </p>
            <p>
               The Applications made of XPages can add features such as :
            </p>
            <p>
               <ul>
                   <li>a search engine</li>
                   <li>the forms (contact, newsletter, formengine)</li>
                   <li>the site plan</li>
                   <li>...</li>
               </ul>
            </p>
            <p>
                The applications are thus completely binded to the site. They
                consists of menus, banners, style sheets of the portal.
                Their graphical appearance will also change during a website upgrade 
                thus no additional work is needed.
            </p>
            
        </subsection>
        <subsection name="Technical description">
            <p>
               An extended page can be distinguished when the url of the page
               has a <b>page</b> parameter and not  <b>id_page</b> as classical pages
               of the site.
            
            </p>
            <p>
               
               For exemple, <code>http://myhost/lutece/jsp/site/Portal.jsp?page=map</code> to
               obtain the site map.
            </p>
            <p>
               The parameter specified the plugin name containing the <code>XPageApp</code>.
            </p>
            <p>
               <i>Note : By convention, we design this parameter in the
               form : <b>&lt;xpage&gt;</b></i>.
            </p>
        </subsection>
        
        <subsection name="JAVA treatment">
           <p>
              When the parameter <b>&lt;page&gt;</b> is detected in the 
              request, the class <b>fr.paris.lutece.portal.web.PortalJspBean</b>
              (entry page of Lutece) calls to the method :
              </p>
              <p>
                 <div class="source">
<pre>
public String getPage( HttpServletRequest request , int nMode )</pre>
                 </div>
                  of 
                    <code>fr.paris.lutece.portal.service.XPageAppService</code> class.
                    
                    The service will look for the plugin whose name is specified 
                    in the parameter <b>page</b> in the request and fetch it from 
                    an instance of the <code>XPageApp</code> class.
                   
               </p>
               <p>
                  All the XPageApp must be implement the interface :
                  
                  <code>fr.paris.lutece.portal.web.xpages.XPageApplication</code>.
               </p>
               <p>
                  It defines the following method :
               </p>
               <p>
                  <div class="source">
     <pre>
public String getContent( HttpServletRequest request, int nMode, Plugin plugin );</pre>
                  </div>
               </p>
               <p>  
                   which returns the page content relative to the parameters contained 
                   in the request, of mode (normal or administration) and
                   the instance of the plugin for which it was instanciated.
                 (The same class can be instanciated in different contexts).
               </p>
               <p>
                  <code>XPageService</code> calls this method and fills a structure
                  <code>XPage</code> with the XPage's own data :
               </p>
               <p>
                  <ul>
                      <li>title of the page in the browser title bar</li>
                      <li>htm content in the page (described previously)</li>
                      <li>the navigation path : "You are Here" with the the context path</li>
                      <li>the key words associated to the page(used by search engines)</li>
                  </ul>
               </p>
           </subsection>
           
           <subsection name="JSP">
              <p>
                 If the XPageApp developed needs an additional processing JSP 
                 (such as sending a message to the contact page), the JSP
                 should be placed in the folder :
                   <code>portal/jsp/site/plugins/&lt;myplugin&gt;</code>. The only
                   imposed ruled is inclusion in the file header :
              </p>
              <p>
                 <div class="source">
     <pre>
&lt;%@ page errorPage="../../ErrorPagePortal.jsp" %&gt;
&lt;jsp:include page="../../PortalHeader.jsp" /&gt;
</pre>
                  </div>
              </p>
           </subsection>
           
           <subsection name="Access to the page">
              <p>
                 There is no automatic links towards the XPages on Lutece.
              </p>
              <p>
                 Normally, the XPages are accessible from the menu situated on 
                 the banner.
              </p>
              <p>
                 Adding an extended page from a properties file do not add
                 automatically the XPage in the menu.
                 The menu is a static menu, the links are written in hard in the template :
                 dur dans le template :
                 <code>WEB-INF/templates/skin/site/page_menu_tools.html</code>.
              </p>
              <p>
                  A LinkService allows to insert from a Wysiwyg HTML editor 
                  an article or an HTML portlet, alink towards XPages on the web site.
              </p>
              
          </subsection>
          
           <subsection name="Page Administration">
              <p>
                 Administrative functions are generally needed to manage the
                 backoffice fetaures.
              </p>
              <p>
                 To create for the same plugin, administrative functions 
                  [ <a href=
                 "howto-create-admin-features.html">HOWTO - Create functions
                 d'administration</a> ]
              </p>
             
           </subsection>
       
           <subsection name="XPage definition in plugin configuration">
               <p>
                   The application must be declared in the XML file of the plugin as follows :
  
                   <div class="source">
                       <pre>
    &lt;!-- Application XPage --&gt;
    &lt;application&gt;
           &lt;application-class&gt;fr.paris.lutece.plugins.myplugin.web.MyPluginApp&lt;/application-class&gt;
           &lt;application-roles&gt;role1,role2&lt;/application-roles&gt;
    &lt;/application&gt;
                       </pre>
                   </div>
               </p>
           </subsection>
           
           <subsection name="Notice">
               <p>
                  The XPages are not indexed by the Lucene search engine.They
                  will,thus, not be visible by a search from the home page.
               </p>
           </subsection>
         </section>
    </body>
</document>


