<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <document>
      <properties>
          <title>
              Lutece : Introduction
          </title>
      </properties>
      <body>
          <section name="Welcome to the Lutece Project ">
              <p>
                  Lutece is a portal engine which allows you to easily create your websites or intranets based upon HTML,XML.. content. 
                  This open-source software is implemented in Java and based on widely used libraries and frameworks : Spring, Freemarker, 
                  Lucene, Ehcache, Jakarta-commons, ... .
                  Lutece provides a user friendly interface for portal management and therefore no specific technical skills are required. 
              </p>
              <p>    
                  Lutece is free and is distributed under a BSD-like license.
              </p>
              <p>
                  Lutece provides an highly modular architecture based on plugins. <a href="available-plugins.html">See available plugins list</a>. 
              </p>
              <p>
                  Languages available are for the moment English and French. 
                  French users are invited to consult the <a href="http://fr.lutece.paris.fr">french site</a>. 
              </p>
          </section>
		  <section name="Project Information">
			<p>
				<a href="project-summary.html">Project Summary</a>: this document lists other related information of this project
			</p>	
			<p>
				<a href="http://dev.lutece.paris.fr/jira/browse/LUTECE" target="_blank">Issue Tracking</a> : this is a link to the issue management system for this project. Issues (bugs, features, change requests) can be created and queried using this link.
			</p>	
			<p>
				<a href="http://dev.lutece.paris.fr/viewvc/portal/trunk/" target="_blank">Source Repository</a> : this is a link to the online source repository that can be viewed via a web browser.
			</p>
			<p>
				<a href="dependencies.html">Dependencies</a> : this document lists the projects dependencies and provides information on each dependency.
			</p>
			<p>
				<a href="license.html">Project License</a> : this is a link to the definitions of project licenses.
			</p>
		  </section>
      </body>
  </document>
          
